现在我们将看一种称为图像变形的非常通用的技术。
Now we’re going to look at a very general technique called image warping.
图像变形可用于对图像执行大量操作，我们就是这样
Image warping can be used to perform a large number of operations on an image and we’re
首先考虑一些非常简单的例子。但它们都可以组合在一起
going to consider some very simple examples first. But they can all be combined together
允许非常复杂的图像变换。
to allow for quite complex image transformations.
当我们讨论单应性时，我们在上一次讲座中触及了图像变形
We did touch on image warping in the last lecture when we were discussing homographies
和观点整改。让我们首先考虑图像缩放的情况。
and perspective rectification. Let’s consider first the case of image scaling.
在这里，我们有一个蒙娜丽莎的输入图像，我想缩小她的一个因素
Here we have an input image of the Mona Lisa and I want to shrink her by a factor of perhaps
每个方向一半。因此，如果输出图像与输入图像的大小相同
a half in each direction. So if the output image is the same size as the input image
然后萎缩的蒙娜丽莎坐在左上角。你会在这里注意到
then the shrunken Mona Lisa sits up in the top left-hand corner. You’ll note here that
输出图像中有大量像素为红色。那是
there are a large number of pixels in the output image which are colored red. That’s
因为对于这些像素，我们不知道它们的价值应该是多少。我们已经缩放了
because for these pixels we don’t have any idea what their value should be. We’ve scaled
蒙娜丽莎的面积是她以前尺寸的四分之一，但我们已将她放在输出图像中
the Mona Lisa to a quarter of her previous size but we’ve placed her in an output image
与输入大小相同，因此有很多像素我们无法使用其值
the same size as the input so there are a whole lot of pixels whose value we are unable
估计。
to estimate.
这是我们将在本节末尾回顾的主题。
This is a topic we’ll come back to at the end of this section.
现在我想结合缩放和移位。所以我们采用原始输入图像，我们就是
Now I want to combine scaling and shifting. So we take our original input image and we’re
要收缩她。我们要把她放到输出图像的中间位置
going to shrink her. We’re going to put her into the middle of the output image so
她的尺寸缩小了，然后偏移到了蒙娜丽莎的左上角
she’s been reduced in size and then offset so that the top left corner of the Mona Lisa
图片不在输出图像的左上角。
picture is not in the top left corner of the output image.
我可以考虑轮换。为了旋转图像，我首先需要确定这一点
I can consider rotation. In order to rotate the image, I first need to decide the point
关于我将轮换。所以我们将在她的下巴下旋转一点
about which I will rotate. So we’ll rotate about a point here just underneath her chin
我们将旋转45度。
and we will rotate by something like 45 degrees.
当我们将这个旋转的图像放入一个与输入图像大小相同的帧时，
When we place this rotated image into a frame which is the same size as the input image,
我们看到了一些有趣的事情。我们首先看到有一些角落
we see a couple of interesting things. We see firstly that there are some corners of
输出图像仍然是红色的。
the output image which is still colored red.
那是没有有效像素的地方。我们也看到了蒙娜丽莎的角落
That’s where there are no valid pixels. We also see that the corners of the Mona Lisa
在图像外面粘贴的东西必须被砍掉。所以通过旋转
which stick outside the image are going to have to be chopped off. So by rotating the
蒙娜丽莎，我们丢失了原始图像的一些角落，并且输出中有一些角落
Mona Lisa, we lose some corners of the original image and there are some corners of the output
未设置的图像。
image which are unset.
那么我们就可以将移位，缩放和旋转结合在一起进行一次整体转换，
So then we can combine shifting, scaling and rotation all together into one overall transformation,
输入图像到输出图像。为了形式化，我们将定义
the input image to the output image. In order to formalize this, we’re going to define
输入图像中像素的坐标使用符号U和V，就像我们已经完成的那样
the coordinate of a pixel in the input image using the notation U and V as we’ve done
通过这个课程。我们将定义相应的坐标
all through this course. We’re going to define the coordinate of the corresponding
在输出图像中指向，我将用U-prime和V-prime表示那些。所以
point in the output image and I’m going to denote those by U-prime and V-prime. So
我们可以编写一个非常通用的函数，U-prime，作为两个输入坐标的函数
we can write a very general function, U-prime, as a function of the two input coordinates
和V-prime作为两个输入坐标的函数。
and V-prime as a function of the two input coordinates.
所以在这两个通用函数fU和fV中，我们可以描述缩放，移位，旋转，
So in these two general functions fU and fV, we can describe scaling, shifting, rotating,
这些以及许多其他非常有趣的扭曲的各种组合。您
various combinations of those and many other kinds of very interesting distortions. You
可以做funhouse镜面效果等。
can do funhouse mirror effects and so on.
让我们看一下缩放和移位的具体例子，我们实际上是如何做的
Let’s look at a concrete example of scaling and shifting, how we actually go about doing
那。我们将在输入图像中定义一个像素，坐标U，V，它是正确的
that. We’re going to define a pixel in the input image, coordinates U, V and it’s right
在蒙娜丽莎眼中。我们将定义相应的点
in the middle of the Mona Lisa’s eye. We’re going to define the corresponding point in
输出图像及其坐标IU-prime和V-prime。此输出图像是四分之一
the output image and its coordinates I U-prime and V-prime. This output image is one quarter
输入图像的大小，水平偏移100，垂直偏移200。所以我们
the size of the input image and it’s offset 100 horizontally and 200 vertically. So we
可以在U-prime和U之间以及V-prime和V之间写出一个非常简单的关系。
can write a very simple relationship between U-prime and U and between V-prime and V.
现在我们要做的是尽可能考虑输出图像中的每个像素
Now what we’re going to do is to consider every pixel in the output image, every possible
U-prime和V-prime的值。对于我们所看到的U-prime和V-prime的每个值
value of U-prime and V-prime. For every value of U-prime and V-prime that we look at in
在输出图像中，我们可以计算出输入图像中U和V的值。
the output image, we can compute what will be the value of U and V in the input image.
因此，我们查看输出图像中的每个像素，然后我们计算它的来源
So we look at every pixel in the output image and we work out where it comes from in the
输入图像。所以我们实际上必须反转我们之前写的那些一般方程，
input image. So we have to in fact invert those general equations that we wrote earlier,
fU和fV。在这里，我们将它们颠倒过来，以便我们现在有了U和V.
the fU and the fV. Here we have inverted them so that we’ve got U and V now in terms of
输出像素坐标，U-prime和V-prime。
the output pixel coordinates, U-prime and V-prime.
让我们用一个例子来说明这一点。让我们选择输出像素
Let’s use an example to make this very tangible. Let’s choose for example the output pixel
在坐标303和269.鉴于此，很容易计算出坐标
at coordinate 303 and 269. Given that, it’s very easy to work out the coordinate of the
输入图像中的像素。
pixel in the input image.
有趣的是，输入图像中的像素是分数。我们正在寻找像素
Interestingly, the pixel in the input image is fractional. We’re looking for the pixel
在50.75和17.25，这有点问题，因为像素有整数坐标;
at 50.75 and 17.25 and this is a bit problematic because pixels have got integer coordinates;
到目前为止我们看过的U和V一直是整数值。那我们怎么走
U and V that we’ve looked at so far have always been integer values. So how do we go
关于在输入图像中找到这个小数像素值？
about finding this fractional pixel value in the input image?
让我们考虑一下我们在这里显示的输入图像的一小块补丁
Let’s consider that we’ve got a little patch of the input image shown here in a very
放大时尚。所以我们正在寻找的特定像素实际上就是这样
zoomed-in fashion. So the particular pixel that we’re looking for would actually lay
在我们的像素值网格中的某处。我们可以使用一些策略
somewhere here in our grid of pixel values. There are a few strategies that we can use
确定此处所示的此特定坐标处的像素的虚值
to determine the imaginary value of the pixel at this particular coordinate shown here by
黄点。
the yellow dot.
我们可以做的第一件事是获取最接近的像素的值，所以黄色
The first thing we can do is to take the value of the pixel that’s closest, so the yellow
dot位于此处显示的像素范围内，其值为115.所以我们可以
dot lies within the bounds of the pixel shown here that’s got a value of 115. So we can
只是说像素值等于115.但它位于该特定的底部
just say the pixel value is equal to 115. But it’s in the bottom corner of that particular
像素，所以你认为隔壁的117，它下面的123实际上可能会提升
pixel so you’d think that the 117 next door, the 123 beneath it might actually elevate
那里的价值。一个更复杂的方法是采取加权平均值
the value there. A more sophisticated approach then is to take a weighted average of the
相邻像素和权重与像素中心之间的距离成比例
neighboring pixel and the weights are proportional to the distance between the pixel center and
这里标有黄点。这是一种被称为双线性插值的技术。
the yellow dot marked here. This is the technique that’s referred to as bilinear interpolation.
它也可以被认为是适合这四个点的平面。像素值代表
It can also be thought of as fitting a plane to these four points. The pixel values represent
表面的高度。我们可以将飞机安装到这四个点然后我们可以确定
the height of the surface. We can fit a plane to those four points and then we can determine
该平面在黄点的U，V坐标处的高度。
the height of that plane at the U, V coordinate of the yellow dot.
现在让我们考虑如果我在这里选择一个像素会发生什么。所以这个输出像素，这个
Let’s consider now what happens if I choose a pixel down here. So this output pixel, this
U-prime和V-prime的特定值位于输出中的MonaLisa图像之外
particular value of U-prime and V-prime, lays outside the Mona Lisa image in the output
图片。这里发生了什么？如果我们取这个特定的输出像素坐标，500，
image. What’s going on here? If we take this particular output pixel coordinate, 500,
300，我们将它映射到输入图像中的坐标，我们发现它在外面
300 and we map it to the coordinate in the input image, we find that it lays way outside
输入图像。所以我们可以使用一些非常简单的逻辑来表示输入图像坐标
the input image. So we can use some pretty simple logic to say that an input image coordinate
像1600,400在输入图像的边界之外。
like 1600, 400 lays outside the bounds of the input image.
因此，我们没有在该特定点放入输出图像的值。
Therefore, we don’t have a value to put into the output image at that particular point.
如果这是一个双精度输出图像，我们可能会使用非常特殊的双精度
If this was a double-precision output image, we might use the very special double-precision
值不是数字或NaN来表示我们无法确定其值的像素。
value known as not a number or NaN to represent pixels whose value we are unable to determine.
如果它是整数输出图像，我们可能会保留一个特定的整数值
If it was an integer output image, we might reserve a particular integer value, perhaps
零，可能是255，表示我们无法确定其值的像素。
zero, perhaps 255, to represent the pixels whose value we are unable to determine.